Choirunnisa

Email | Whatsapp | linkedin | Portfolio | Indonesia

PROFILE

I'm an Accounting graduate from Universitas Mercu Buana Yogyakarta with a GPA of 3.50, currently transitioning into Back-End development. While working as a Freelance Virtual Assistant, I gained experience in tasks such as data entry, email management, research, customer support, and other administrative functions, which helped me improve my organizational and problem-solving skills. I recently completed a Java bootcamp at EnigmaCamp, where I learned Java, Spring Boot, and MySQL.

EDUCATION

EnigmaCamp IT Bootcamp

2024 - Present

Program: Java, Docker, SpringBoot, JUnit, Javascript, ReactJS, MySQL

- Hands-on experience developing backend applications with Java
- Focus on back-end development with SpringBoot and building scalable systems with Docker
- · Completed practical projects involving RESTful APIs and MySQL database management

Universitas Mercu Buana Yogyakarta

2018 - 2023

Bachelor's Degree of Accounting - GPA 3.50/4.00

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

FREELANCE VIRTUAL ASISSTANT

Oct 2024 - Present

- Managed and organized data entry tasks in Excel, ensuring accuracy and efficient access to essential information.
- Coordinated administrative tasks, including scheduling appointments and booking tickets or making reservations for personal or business needs, ensuring timely and accurate arrangements.
- Conducted in-depth market research, providing insights on industry trends, competitor activities, and customer behaviors to inform business decisions.

FREELANCE PRIVATE TUTOR

Apr 2021 - Present

- Successfully helped over 30 students, with many achieving excellent grades and securing positions in the top 5 in their schools.
- Designed and implemented customized lesson plans to arrange to the unique learning styles and needs of each student.
- Developed interactive and engaging educational materials to enhance the learning experience.
- · Encouraged and motivated students to achieve their academic goals through personalized guidance and support.

CERTIFICATION & COURSE

• EDX - HarvardX - CS50's Introduction to Computer Science	(Jan 2024)
Coursera - IBM - Back-End Development	(Feb 2024)
Coursera - Meta - Meta Front-End Developer	(Feb 2024)
Coursera - Meta - Meta React Native	(Feb 2024)
 Coursera - Johns Hopkins University - HTML, CSS, and Javascript for Web Developers 	(Feb 2024)
Coursera - IBM - Full Stack Software Developer	(Feb 2024)

PROJECTS

Rent Tent

A backend program for managing camping rentals. Built using Java Spring Boot, REST API, JWT for authentication, MySQL for database, and integrated with a Weather API for real-time weather updates.

User Management

A backend system built with Java Spring Boot and Redis for managing user authentication and data caching. Implemented paging and sorting features to optimize data retrieval.

UMKM

This UMKM application is designed to help small businesses manage their finances and product stock. It also records purchase transactions, reduces product stock, and increases the seller's wallet balance whenever a purchase is made. This project uses Java Spring boot, REST API, Spring IOC, Native SQL Query.

Stock Calculator

An online calculator for calculating stock investment values and potential returns. Developed using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

- Allows users to input stock prices, number of shares, and investment periods to calculate estimated investment returns.
- Displays calculation results with clear and intuitive visualizations to facilitate user understanding of investment outcomes.

Travellion

A travel website created using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

- Designed and implemented a user-friendly interface for exploring destinations, booking flights, hotels, and tours.
- Utilized static data and content to display information about destinations, accommodations, and travel packages.

ORGANIZATION & VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCES

Kelompok Studi Pasar Modal UMBY

Staff Of Academic Division

Feb 2020 – June 2021

- Successfully organized 5+ academic events, such as seminars, workshops, and conferences related to the capital market domain, fostering educational initiatives and knowledge dissemination.
- Executed a comprehensive capital market training program with an attendance of 300+ participants, enhancing financial literacy and understanding among a wide audience.
- Conducted internal organizational training sessions with an active participation of 70+ members, boosting the knowledge and skills ofthe team in market dynamics and financial concepts.

Kampus Mengajar

Teacher Assistant at SDN Balirejo

Aug 2021 - Des 2021

- Collaborated with teachers to develop and implement lesson plans and assessments that resulted in a 40% increase in students achievement.
- Created and maintained a positive and supportive learning environment in the classroom, as evidenced by a 40% reduction in student disciplinary issues.
- Developed and implemented a new system for tracking student progress and identifying areas for improvement, which has led to 40% increase in the number of students meeting or exceeding grade-level expectations.
- Increased student engagement and participation in class by 60% by developing and implementing interactive learning activities.
- Helped students to improve their academic performance by 30% by providing individualized instruction and support.

Himpunan Mahasiswa Akuntansi

Staff Of PSDM

Jan 2019 – Jan 2020

- Successfully organized a series of events and workshops on accounting and finance, which attracted over 300 participants.
- Developed and implemented a new system for managing and tracking data on student membership, which has improved efficiency and accuracy by 15%.
- Increased brand awareness and membership for Himpunan Mahasiswa Akuntansi by 30%.

SKILL

Skill : JUnit, Java, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, GIT, Communication, SpringBoot, Redis, Docker, SQL, AWS, REST API

Language: Bahasa Indonesia (Native), English (Limited Working Proficiency), Deutsch (Intermediate)